<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="new_extension">

	<copyright>
        Copyright 2012 Intel Corporation All Rights Reserved.
        The source code contained or described herein and all documents related to
        the source code ("Material") are owned by Intel Corporation or its suppliers
        or licensors. Title to the Material remains with Intel Corporation or its
        suppliers and licensors. The Material contains trade secrets and proprietary
        and confidential information of Intel or its suppliers and licensors. The
        Material is protected by worldwide copyright and trade secret laws and
        treaty provisions. No part of the Material may be used, copied, reproduced,
        modified, published, uploaded, posted, transmitted, distributed, or
        disclosed in any way without Intel’s prior express written permission.
       
        No license under any patent, copyright, trade secret or other intellectual
        property right is granted to or conferred upon you by disclosure or delivery
        of the Materials, either expressly, by implication, inducement, estoppel or
        otherwise. Any license under such intellectual property rights must be
        express and approved by Intel in writing.

		Unless otherwise agreed by Intel in writing, you may not remove or alter
		this notice or any other notice embedded in Materials by Intel or Intel’s
		suppliers or licensors in any way.
	</copyright>

	<interface name="early_camera_plugin" version="1">
		<description summary="early camera interface">
			This is a sample protocol can use by camera client to 
			the plugin for requesting compositor to do something
			it's more an example of how to hook up extensions in 
			the plugin framework.
		</description>

		<request name="create_camera_buffer">
			<description summary="Requests grid cells to start/stop rotating">
				Allows a client to request that the cells of the plugin's
				4x4 grid begin to rotate in the specified manner.
			</description>

			<arg name="method" type="uint" />
		</request>

		<enum name="rotate_cells_method">
			<entry name="none" value="0" summary="Stop cell rotation" />
			<entry name="cw" value="1" summary="Rotate cells clockwise" />
			<entry name="ccw" value="2" summary="Rotate cells counter-clockwise" />
		</enum>

		<event name="cell_selected">
			<description summary="Grid cell click notification">
				This event is raised when the grid cell associated with a
				surface is selected (clicked or switched to via keyboard).
			</description>

			<arg name="cell" type="uint" />
		</event>
	</interface>

</protocol>

