<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="iaslayout">
	<copyright>
		Copyright (c) 2013, Intel Corporation.

		Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
		of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
		in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
		to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
		copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
		furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

		The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
		all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

		THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
		IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
		FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
		AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
		LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
		OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
		THE SOFTWARE.
	</copyright>

	<interface name="ias_layout_manager" version="1">
		<description summary="IAS display layout manager">
			In automotive settings it is quite common to have the same set
			of surfaces be displayed in different layouts during different
			modes of operation (e.g., "home screen" vs task switcher vs
			tiled view).  This interface allows clients to control/monitor
			the usage of different display layouts.
		</description>

		<event name="layout">
			<description summary="Advertises a supported layout">
				A layout event is raised for each layout that the layout
				manager is aware of.  This includes both built-in layouts
				and plugin-loaded layouts.  Layouts are identified by ID
				number.  ID's less than 64 are reserved for builtin layouts
				provided by the IAS shell.  ID's 64 and above are available
				for use by layouts loaded by plugin (the ID assignment can
				be configured in the IAS configuration file).  ID 0 will always
				refer to the 'default' layout (sometimes called the "home
				screen") in which surfaces are organized exactly as specified
				by their internal geometry.
			</description>

			<arg name="id" type="uint" />
			<arg name="name" type="string" />
		</event>

		<event name="layout_switched">
			<description summary="Notify clients of layout change">
				Full detail, full framerate rendering may not be necessary
				or desirable in all display layouts.  This event provides
				a hint to applications that the display layout has changed,
				allowing them to make appropriate adjustments.  For example,
				in a grid layout where surfaces are only visible as thumbnails,
				a GPS app may elect to render in lower quality and possibly
				omit point of interest geometry to lessen the load on the
				GPU.  A media player could elect to pause completely.
			</description>

			<arg name="id" type="uint" />
			<arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output" />
		</event>

		<request name="set_layout">
			<description summary="Set a specific layout">
				Requests that the shell switch to a specific layout on
				specified output.  "layout_switched" event will be delivered to
				each client to notify it about the change.
			</description>

			<arg name="output" type="object" interface="wl_output" />
			<arg name="id" type="uint" />
		</request>
	</interface>
</protocol>
