<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="iasbackend">

    <copyright>
        Copyright (c) 2012, Intel Corporation.

        Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
        of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
        in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
        to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
        copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
        furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

        The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
        all copies or substantial portions of the Software.

        THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
        IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
        FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
        AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
        LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
        OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
        THE SOFTWARE.
    </copyright>

    <interface name="ias_mode" version="1">
        <description summary="CRTC mode">
            Represents a possible width, height, and refresh rate of a CRTC.
        </description>
        <request name="add">
            <description summary="add information about the mode">
				Do nothing for now. This is to force the interface to
				get created.
            </description>
        </request>
    </interface>

    <interface name="ias_crtc" version="1">
        <description summary="CRTC hardware">
            A CRTC represents a hardware pipe.  Each CRTC has a primary display
            plane and possibly one or more sprite planes.  During normal
            operation a CRTC drives exactly one output, but in dualview/stereo
            setups, it is possible to drive two outputs from a single CRTC.
        </description>

        <event name="mode">
            <description summary="Advertises supported mode">
                Advertises a mode that the CRTC supports.  Note that in dualview
                and stereo setups, this mode is actually a combination of the
                modes of the two displays being driven.
            </description>

            <arg name="mode_number" type="uint" />
            <arg name="width" type="uint" />
            <arg name="height" type="uint" />
            <arg name="refresh" type="uint" />
        </event>
        
        <event name="gamma">
            <description summary="Advertises current gamma">
                Advertises the current gamma setting for the CRTC.
            </description>

            <arg name="red" type="uint" />
            <arg name="green" type="uint" />
            <arg name="blue" type="uint" />
        </event>

        <event name="contrast">
            <description summary="Advertises current contrast">
                Advertises the current contrast setting for the CRTC.
            </description>

            <arg name="red" type="uint" />
            <arg name="green" type="uint" />
            <arg name="blue" type="uint" />
        </event>

        <event name="brightness">
            <description summary="Advertises current brightness">
                Advertises the current brightness setting for the CRTC.
            </description>

            <arg name="red" type="uint" />
            <arg name="green" type="uint" />
            <arg name="blue" type="uint" />
        </event>

        <request name="set_mode">
            <description summary="Switch CRTC mode">
                Changes the mode of a CRTC.  Note that in cases where a CRTC is
                driving multiple displays, this will result in a mode change on
                both of those displays.
            </description>

            <arg name="mode" type="uint" />
        </request>

        <request name="set_gamma">
            <description summary="Set CRTC gamma correction">
                Sets the gamma correction for a CRTC.
            </description>

            <arg name="red" type="uint" />
            <arg name="green" type="uint" />
            <arg name="blue" type="uint" />
        </request>

        <request name="set_contrast">
            <description summary="Set CRTC contrast">
                Sets the contrast for a CRTC.
            </description>

            <arg name="red" type="uint" />
            <arg name="green" type="uint" />
            <arg name="blue" type="uint" />
        </request>

        <request name="set_brightness">
            <description summary="Set CRTC brightness">
                Sets the brightness for a CRTC.
            </description>

            <arg name="red" type="uint" />
            <arg name="green" type="uint" />
            <arg name="blue" type="uint" />
        </request>

    </interface>

    <interface name="ias_output" version="1">
        <description summary="Display output">
            An output represents a distinct display (or one "view" of a
            dualview display).  In normal setups there is a single
            output per CRTC.  In dualview and stereo 3D setups, there are
            two outputs per CRTC.
        </description>

        <request name="set_xy">
            <description summary="Set output location">
                Sets the location of the output.
            </description>

            <arg name="x" type="uint" />
            <arg name="y" type="uint" />
        </request>

        <request name="disable">
            <description summary="Disables a display output">
                Disables a display output.  Disabling a display will not adjust
                the compositor coordinates of the other displays managed by the
                compositor.  If two outputs are being driven off a single CRTC,
                this will have no effect on the other output.
            </description>
        </request>

        <request name="enable">
            <description summary="Enables a display output">
                Enables a previously disabled display output.  If two outputs
                are being driven off a single CRTC, this will have no effect on
                the other output.
            </description>
        </request>

        <request name="scale_to">
            <description summary="Scales an output">
                Scales an output to cover a smaller or larger area than the
                output's mode.
            </description>

            <arg name="width" type="uint" />
            <arg name="height" type="uint" />
        </request>

		<request name="set_fb_transparency">
			<description summary="Set Wayland output's transparency">
				Enables or disables transparency in the pixel format for the fb.
			</description>

			<arg name="enable" type="uint" />
		</request>

		<event name="name">
			<description summary="Output name">
				Advertises the name of this output.
			</description>
			
			<arg name="name" type="string" />
		</event>

    </interface>
</protocol>
